なんで… うっ！
Why...?
なんで わからねえんだ！
Why don't you get it?!
もうじき お前の体は…➡
Soon, Orochimaru's going
to take your body!
大蛇丸に とられちまうんだぞ！
(サスケ)そうなったら そうなっただ。
If it happens, it happens...
子供のままだな… ナルト。
You're still a kid, Naruto.
オレにとっては 復讐がすべてだ。
Revenge is everything to me.
復讐さえ叶えば
オレがどうなろうが➡
If I can carry out my revenge,
it's no concern of mine
what happens to me,
この世がどうなろうが
知ったことじゃない…。
or to this world.
はっきり言うとだ…➡
Put simply, neither I nor Orochimaru
can defeat Itachi right now.
イタチは 今のオレでも
大蛇丸でも倒せない。
だが 大蛇丸に
オレの体を差し出すことで➡
But if I can obtain the power
to accomplish that
それを成し得る力を
手にできるなら…➡
by giving my body to Orochimaru,
こんな命 いくらでもくれてやる！
then I'll give him as much of
this life of mine as he wants.
Title
(ヤマト)話は終わりだ…。
The talking's over.
(ヤマト)ナルトとサクラ… キミたちの手前➡
Naruto and Sakura...
I didn't want to do anything rough
in front of you guys...
彼に手荒なマネは
したくなかったが➡
悪いが… もう本気でやるよ！
but I'm going to get serious now.
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
本気で って…。
What do you mean, serious...?
(ヤマト)大蛇丸同様
里抜けした者を➡
I can't just let those
who left the village in the same way
as Orochimaru run loose.
野放しにしとく
わけにもいかないしね。
(ヤマト)どんな手を使ってでも
彼を木ノ葉に連行する。
So I'll do whatever I have to do
to haul Sasuke back to the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉か…。
The Hidden Leaf, huh...?
お前たちは もういい…。
I've had enough of you guys...
終わりだ！
It's over.
大蛇丸…！
Orochimaru...
(大蛇丸)その術は
やめておきなさい… サスケ君。
Don't bother with that Jutsu, Sasuke.
放せ…。
Let go of me...
(カブト)こらこら…。
Hey-hey...
大蛇丸様に向かって
またそんな口の利き方を…。
Don't talk to
Lord Orochimaru like that...
やめる理由はない…。
I've got no reason to stop.
今の暁の動きを
キミも知ってるよね？
You know what the Akatsuki
are up to, don't you?
(カブト)この木ノ葉の人たちには➡
We want these guys from
the Hidden Leaf
暁を始末しておいて
もらいたいんだよ。
to take care of the Akatsuki for us.
１人でも多くね…。
As many of them as possible...
他の暁に ジャマされると➡
Your revenge won't turn out well
キミの復讐も
うまくいかなくなるだろ。
if the other Akatsuki
get in the way, right?
情けない理由だな。
That's a pathetic reason.
復讐の可能性を
１％でも上げるためだよ。
It should increase your chances of revenge,
even if only by one percent...
そうだろ？
Isn't that right?
行くわよ。
Let's go.
あっ！
《また…
また止められなかった…》
Once again...
Once again...I couldn't stop him...
《オレは… よえぇ…》
I'm...totally weak...
(サクラ)泣いたって… 泣いたって
サスケ君は 帰ってこないでしょ。
Crying...
Crying won't bring Sasuke back home!
I'm here! I'll get stronger with you!
私も いる。
私だって 一緒に強くなる！
(サイ)時間… あと半年近くは
あるんだよね。
We've got...
close to six months left, right?
(サイ)２人より ３人のほうが
いいに決まってる。
It goes without saying that three
are better than two.
それに ボクは 結構 強いからね。
Besides, I'm pretty strong myself.
ありがとう。
Thanks...
さて…。
Now then...
《これからだな…》
This is just the beginning...
(トントン)ブヒッ！
(綱手)そうか…。
I see...
はぁ…。
Hidden Leaf Hospital
(カカシ)なんですって!?
ナルトたちが サスケと？
What did you say?!
Naruto and the others fought Sasuke?!
(自来也)うん。
しかし➡
Yes...
But, their original mission was to...
アイツらの本来の任務は…。
そう あやつらの任務は➡
Yes, their mission was to capture
the spy Sasori sent to Orochimaru
サソリが大蛇丸のもとに送り込んだ
スパイを拘束➡
木ノ葉に連れ帰ること。
and bring him back to the Hidden Leaf,
大蛇丸やサスケの情報を
得るためにもな。
and to get information about Orochimaru
and Sasuke as well.
だが サソリのスパイ 薬師 カブトは➡
But Sasori's spy, Kabuto Yakushi,
大蛇丸によって すでに
サソリの術を解かれておった。
already had Sasori's Jutsu
broken by Orochimaru.
そして 大蛇丸は この機に➡
And it seems Orochimaru tried to use
this opportunity to kill Sasori,
サソリを亡き者に
しようとしていたらしい。
本物のサソリが すでに
死んでいることを知らずにのう。
not knowing that the real Sasori
was already dead...
大蛇丸と接触した ナルトは
感情を抑えきれなくなり 暴走。
Naruto made contact with Orochimaru,
became unable to
control his emotions...
and ran amuck.
ナルトは ついに ４本目の尾まで出し
暴れまくった。
Naruto eventually
released his fourth tail...
and went wild.
さしもの大蛇丸も
九尾状態のナルトと やりあって➡
Orochimaru did battle
with the Nine-Tails Naruto.
限界を迎えたのじゃろう。
Even he probably reached his limit...
ヤマトが ナルトを押さえ込む間に
姿を消そうとしたようだ。
Stabilize
It seems he tried to disappear
while Yamato was attempting
to control Naruto.
しかし ヤマトの分身が 密かに追跡。
However, Yamato's clone secretly
pursued Orochimaru.
ついに 大蛇丸のアジトを突き止め
内部に進入。
Finally, they found Orochimaru's hideout
and made their way in.
そこで サスケと遭遇し
戦闘になったらしい。
Then it seems they encountered Sasuke
and a battle ensued.
それで どうなったんです？
So...then what happened?
サスケは
相当 力をつけとったらしい。
It seems Sasuke has become
significantly more powerful...
(自来也)ナルトは
まるで 歯が立たんかったそうだ。
I hear Naruto didn't stand
a chance against him...
はぁ… そうですか。
I see...
まぁ そう落ち込むな。
Well, don't get so depressed.
ナルトは 九尾化のダメージで➡
It appears Naruto wasn't able
to show his full power
十分に
力を出せんかったようだし➡
because of damage from
the Nine-Tails Cloak.
それに…。
いえ。
And...
No. I'm not all that depressed,
you know.
それほど 落ち込んでるわけじゃ
ないですよ。
現時点では サスケのほうが上だと
思ってましたし➡
I figured Sasuke would be stronger
at this point in time...
それに…。
And...
(カカシ)
サスケとの差を自覚したことで➡
Now Naruto will be more fired up
for future training
これからの修業にも
気合が入る。
after having realized the difference
between Sasuke and himself.
でしょう？
Right?
フン だのう。
Right.
まぁ 今回は
無事に帰ってきただけで➡
Well, I guess we should be happy
they made it back safe.
よしとしましょう。
(ホムラ)ナルトが 無事に帰ってきたのは
幸運じゃったな。
It's fortunate that Naruto
was able to make it back safely.
(コハル)しかし 任務には
不測の事態がつきものとはいえ➡
However, although unexpected situations
are an inevitable part of missions...
まさか 大蛇丸と
やりあうことになるとは。
I never thought he would end up
doing battle with Orochimaru...
(コハル)こういうことがあるから➡
And here, it's best to keep Naruto
in the village
ナルトは 里に とどめておいたほうが
よいのに…。
because things like this
end up happening...
(ホムラ)あの頑固者が 簡単に
意見を曲げるとは思えんしな。
I don't think that hard-head
would depart from his opinions so easily.
う～ん…。
はぁ…。
…で？
オレたちは あきらめねえ。
So?
We aren't giving up!
フッ では お前たちには
すぐ 次の任務を言い渡す。
Okay, I will issue
your next mission immediately.
おって連絡があるまで
自宅待機。
Stand by at home until I contact you!
おう！
Right!
なぁ サクラちゃん
このまま ２人でデートしようか。
Hey, Sakura.
Let's go on a date together.
アンタ たった今 綱手様に
言われたこと 忘れたの？
Have you forgotten what Lady Tsunade
said just now?
あ？ 何だっけ？
Huh?! What'd she say again?
私たち カカシ班は 次の任務が
決まるまで 自宅待機でしょ？
We're supposed to stand by at home
until Team Kakashi's next mission
has been determined, right?!
あぁ ちょっとだけなら
ばれねえってばよ。
What? She won't find out if
we just go out for a little while!
(サクラ)デートしたいなら
１人ですれば？
Why don't you go by yourself
if you want to go out on a date?
いや １人じゃできねえってばよ。
I won't be able to
go on a date by myself.
(綱手)ところで サイの動きは？
By the way, what about Sai's activity?
はい 綱手様が
心配されていたとおり➡
Yes. You were right
to be concerned, Lady Tsunade.
ダンゾウから
特別任務を与えられていました。
Danzo gave him a special mission.
特別任務？
A special mission?!
《シズネ : やはり…》
I knew it...
(ヤマト)サイは ダンゾウの指示で
暗部として 任務をこなしつつ➡
It seems Sai was put in charge
of undercover work,
dealing with potential risks
to the Hidden Leaf
木ノ葉に対する危険人物の➡
while carrying out his mission as
諜報活動 および 処理に
当たっていたようです。
an Anbu Black Ops member
under Danzo's direction.
サイが 今回
ボクたち カカシ班に合流した目的は➡
Sai's purpose for joining us in
Team Kakashi was to bury Sasuke,
木ノ葉が もっとも注意すべき人物
大蛇丸…。
who is to become the new vessel
for Orochimaru,
the individual of most concern
to the Hidden Leaf.
その大蛇丸の 新たなる肉体
サスケを葬ることだった。
えっ!?
What?!
フン… 食えない男だと
思っていたが。
I figured he was a crafty guy...
方法は 武闘派路線の
主導者だけあって 強引だが➡
As would be expected of the leader
of a hard-line military faction,
his actions are strong-armed.
But our protective feelings
for the Hidden Leaf are the same, huh...?
木ノ葉を思う気持は
ひとつということか。
それは ダンゾウのことを
おっしゃっているのですか？
Are you talking about Danzo?
ん？ そうだが…。
Yes, I am...
では 結論は これをご覧に
なってからにしてもらえますか。
Then could you hold off on
your conclusions until you see this?
(綱手)これは？
What's this?
Danzo gave this to Sai as
a gift for Orochimaru
ダンゾウが 大蛇丸との接触を
円滑に進めるために➡
サイに持たせた
大蛇丸への手土産です。
in order for the contact with Orochimaru
to proceed smoothly.
Wh-What's this?!
こ… これは！
暗部の構成員リスト！
It's a list of Anbu Black Ops members!
《クソ… ダンゾウのヤツ！
Damn it! That jerk, Danzo!
極秘ファイルの中から
リストを どうやって手に入れた!?》
How did he get the list from
the classified files...?
あの 綱手様…。
Um...Lady Tsunade...
シズネ！ 極秘ファイル倉庫への
警備の強化 および➡
Shizune! Tighten security at
the classified files storehouse
and change the deciphering codes
for the files. Quickly!
ファイルの解読暗号の変更を急げ！
あ… はい！
Y-Yes ma'am!
今すぐだ！
あひぃ～！
Right now!
アハハハハ…。
クソ！ あのタヌキじじい…
どこまでいっても 食えないヤツだ。
Damn it! That sly old dog...
He's always the crafty one!
(綱手)大蛇丸 暁と
里の外が騒がしいってときに➡
At a time when the outside
of the village
is in an uproar with Orochimaru
and the Akatsuki...
里内部のごたごたまで
考えなきゃならんとは…。
I never thought I'd have to be concerned
about trouble inside  the village...
これでは 先ほどの サイの申し入れ
慎重に考えざるをえんな。
Now I'll be forced to consider Sai's
earlier proposal with caution.
それでしたら…。
In that case...
ん…？
(ダンゾウ)特別任務をしくじるとは…。
お前らしくないな。
I never thought you'd fail
the special mission...
That's very unlike you...
(サイ)ひとつ お願いがございます。
I have a favor to ask.
A favor, you say?
(ダンゾウ)願い… だと？
(サイ)はい。
Yes.
この名のまま しばらく➡
Could you keep me in Team Kakashi
under this name for a while?
カカシ班に身を置かせては
いただけないでしょうか？
《この笑い顔は…》
That smile on his face...
(ダンゾウ)その話なら
綱手からも受けている。
I've already taken that up
with Tsunade.
But you understand that emotions
create hate, don't you, Sai?
しかし… わかっているな？ サイ。
感情は 憎しみを作り出す。 そして
憎しみは 戦いを作り出すものだ。
And hate creates battles.
((兄との憎しみっていう
つながりがな))
Bonds of hatred with
my older brother...
That might be so.
(サイ)そうかもしれませんね。
《でも…》
But...
((アイツは 誰よりも オレのことを
認めてくれた１人だ。
He's the person who acknowledged
me more than anyone else.
サスケは オレの友達だ。
Sasuke is my friend.
(やっとできた 大切なつながりだ))
((お前 「仲間」って言葉
知ってっか？
(もちろん 知ってますが…
それが 何か？))
≪お～い サイ！
次の任務の
打ち合わせだってばよ！
≪早くしろってばよ！
(サイ)あぁ 今 行くよ。
たっだいま…。
フゥ…。
(カカシ)はいは～い！ 写真撮るから
みんな ちゃんとして。
なんで オレ様が コイツなんかと➡
一緒に写らなきゃ
いけねえんだってばよ！
こっちのセリフだ うすらトンカチ！
なっ… なんだとぉ！
まぁまぁ… これ 決まりだから。
でも 嬉しいなぁ！ サスケ君と
一緒に写れるなんて！
オレも！ オレも！ サクラちゃんと
写れて 超嬉しいってば！
先生… ナルトは外してください。
ガ～ン… そんなぁ…。
フン…。
笑うな！
あん？
(カカシ)いい加減にしろ ２人とも。
写真屋さんも困ってるでしょ。
(カカシ)ほら… これ 残るんだから
笑って 笑って！
(カカシ)はい！ じゃあ
お願いしま～す！